John Nam

Software Engineer - Fairfax, VA 703-307-7908 – Jungwoo9543@gmail.com Linkedin - Github - Portfolio

I am a Software Engineer with a background in Applied Mathematics and experience within the healthcare and IT industry. My interests generally lie in the areas of Backend Development and Full Stack Development. I enjoy the process of problemsolving and love learning about the underlying algorithmic solutions! My favorite language is in python and JavaScript.

SKILLS

Languages - Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, JSON || Database - MongoDB, PSQL || Libraries & Frameworks - React (class based & hooks), Express.js, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap || Other - RESTful Routing, API, Postman

PROJECTS

AdventureTime October 2022

(*Django, PSQL, Python*) Built a full-stack application using Django with full CRUD functions. Included user authentication method with PSQL Database to update the model of the project. Worked solo.

Travelizer September 2022

(React, JavaScript) Built a full-stack application using React to fetch all data from Public API for the user to choose and favorite which countries they want to travel to. Worked solo.

Instagram Cloning August 2022

(EJS, MongoDB, JavaScript, Postman) Collaborated on 3-person team to deconstruct structure of current popular social media platform. Created multiple wireframes for project. Implemented Authorization method where user could login and connect to each profile. Assisted team to understand RESTful routes.

Tamagotchi August 2022

(JavaScript, HTML, CSS) Built fully functional Tamagotchi character with several interaction button for users to play the game

EXPERIENCE

Violations Processor Analyst

November 2021 - July 2022

BusPatrol | Lorton, VA

- Improved accuracy of statistical information by organizing, recording, and analyzing all data submitted through daily citations which led to increased overall efficiency and growth in revenue.
- Assisted QA team lead with meeting operational objectives by contributing data input and verifying that all documentations were correct and updated to always be ahead of project deadlines

IT Specialist Tier I

January 2020- October 2020

Mindshift Technologies | Tysons Corner, VA

- Resolve product or service problems by clarifying the customer's issue; determining the cause of the problem; selecting and explaining the best solution to solve the problem; expediting correction or adjustment; following up to ensure resolution.
- Manage large amounts of incoming calls and record accurate, valid information through detailed notes

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive Program

July 2022 - October 2022

General Assembly | Remote

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.) in Applied Mathematics

September 2013- May 2018

Virginia Commonwealth University | Richmond, VA

Research Paper: Fibonacci Sequence and it's uses and application